GEORGE WENDAL

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

email wendal@gmail.com phone 443-285-1790

portfolio http://georgewendal.com

OVERVIEW

For the past **twelve years** I've been working to craft thoughtful, intuitive experiences for users across a variety of devices and contexts. My design process is informed by the hundreds of hours I've logged talking with users and observing their behavior, and the products that I've built have been used by **millions of people** across the world.

WORK HISTORY

University of Maryland

July 2013 to Present

UX DESIGNER

Currently leading the design for the Kuali Foundation's new flagship Course Registration product. Course Registration is an open source web application used by higher education institutions to help register students for courses.

My responsibilities include:

- Creating a responsive design allowing students to register for courses on a variety of devices
- Working with stakeholders across multiple institutions to identify business goals
- Conducting user research activities with students and administrators

Lofty Interactive

Oct 2008 to Present

PRINCIPAL DESIGNER/DEVELOPER

Designed and built websites and web applications for the Office of Government Ethics, Viacom, M&T Bank, FTI Consulting, and others.

Social Security Administration

2005 to 2008, 2010 to 2013

UX DESIGNER

As a contractor with Lockheed Martin and Northrop Grumman, I was responsible for leading user experience design activities for projects throughout the SSA, including the development of numerous web applications and websites, both internal and public facing.

UserWorks, Inc.

2002 to 2005

USABILITY SPECIALIST

Conducted usability and accessibility evaluations of websites, software applications, printed materials and more.

EDUCATION

University of Maryland, Baltimore County Bachelor of Arts, Psychology (2002)

Scrum Alliance

Certified Scrum Master (2013)

SKILLS

INTERACTION DESIGN

Responsive Design Hi-fidelity Prototyping Task Flows Storyboards Personas Scenarios Accessibility

USER RESEARCH

Usability Testing Interviewing Contextual Inquiry A/B Testing Card Sorting Surveys

INFORMATION ARCHITECTURE

Wireframes Site Maps Content Inventories

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

CSS Javascript Actionscript 3 Bootstrap **i**Query **AngularJS**

HTML

TOOLS

Axure Photoshop Illustrator Visio Morae